So what is this history mode that it's yelling at us about?
History mode is a way to basically define how you want
your URLs to be displayed.
Traditionally speaking, when you're looking at the view
router docs, and we check it out here.
So just so you know, traditionally, single-page
applications, because they're just the index.html file
when they're served to the web page, what's
known as web hash history.
So typically, what you would find is you would basically
see the root page.
And then it would say router.vjs.org.
And then it'll do this hashtag symbol,
and then it will basically do the routing from there.
The problem with that is that it's not a true URL,
and then there are SEO issues.
And so what most of us are used to instead
is what is termed HTML5 mode, or web history.
And that is, in other words, how you would expect your URLs
to normally look.
And so basically, you need to define which one it is.
So for us, we're going to go ahead and just use the web
hash history right now, because there
are some things you need to configure for the HTML5 mode
that I'm not sure we'll have time to cover.
So inside of our router, we have the history,
and we would say the create web hash history function.
And that can be imported from here.
OK, now that we have this, this should start
to feel a little bit better for the app.
Oh, look, already something is showing up.
Let me go back to app.view for our playground.
And this time, let me go ahead and swap the color out,
though, to white, so that it's actually easier to read.
There we go.
OK, now we're good.
Now, you might notice, though, if we're looking here,
that this is where the hash history is actually showing up.
You see that?
It's already starting to do that.
But you might realize, wait, but didn't we
define a home page?
Like, why isn't that showing up?
And the reason is because View Router
provides us some new built-in components
that's going to make all the difference when it comes to
helping us manage the routing.
So remember how in the SailorView, I was doing the,
I was manually switching the view on stuff.
So we go to app.view for SailorView.
Inside of here, I had this component is that was dynamically swapping it out.
Well, basically, View Router gives us a supercharged version of that,
where we can actually just say, OK, inside of my app.view,
I'm going to drop a thing called RouterView.
And if you notice, my home page has now showed up.
And if I switch over to Pokedex, OK, so we see some errors here
regarding the Pokedex.
And that is because it looks like it
has to do with the fact that there is an asynchronous operation happening.
So again, for the sake of demoing this real quick,
because we want to focus on the routing part and not that,
I'm just going to switch the H1 over to Pokedex real quick.
And then we can see here, there we go.
We have that here, and we go back home.
That switches to the home page.
And that, at its core, is how this all works, right,
if we build it up from scratch.
And so now with the RouterView, you might be thinking, well, OK,
that's nice, but I don't have to memorize the links.
That's not practical.
I want actual links so I can switch it.
And so you might think, OK, well, my natural instinct then
is to create like a nav item, where I have an ahref,
and I'm going to go to slash, Pokedex, and then Pokedex.
And then I'll have one for the home, just like that.
So that might be your first instinct.
But if we do this and click on it,
you'll notice that nothing's happening,
because if we look up here, it's actually changing the URL to something
that's not actually with the hash.
You see this, what I mean, it's like blinking out.
What you want it to do is actually be able to say,
oh, it's actually on this side, because why?
Because ViewRouter is the one responsible for managing that,
not the browser.
So don't worry, it's actually pretty easy to do.
This is actually pretty easy to do.
Rather than using the native anchor tag,
what you end up getting instead is just
like you have RouterView, you have a RouterLink component.
And so that is ViewRouter's way of helping you to manage things
like history, there's a lot of stuff you can do for you.
But the main thing, though, that's
different is that there is a two property rather than an href.
Because again, it's not truly an anchor tag,
it is doing some programmatic stuff underneath the hood
to help you move to the desired pages.
So I'll save that.
And this time, when we swap over,
you can see that it's actually doing it correctly.
And so if we think about the RouterView,
it really is just like the dynamic component.
It's just swapping in and out components.
And then we have that really nice user experience
of having it already be basically automatically
configured for us.
The one thing I will note, in case you're wondering,
is that you're probably thinking, like,
that was a decent amount of setup.
Well, I want you to know, so I'm going to go ahead
and show you this real quick.
This won't be committed as part of the code.
If we go ahead and run the npm create view 3,
whoop, that was the wrong version.
OK.
You might remember that there's actually the opportunity
to actually add ViewRouter as part of your configuration.
We explicitly ignored it because it
does a few things which I'm about to show you.
So I'm going to say yes this time,
and I'll show you what that looks like.
So if we look at the ViewProject now,
you'll notice that it actually looks a bit different.
It comes with more boilerplate now.
So you can see, inside of main.js,
the router is already being used.
There already is a router.js basically already
created with all this base stuff already waiting for you.
Regarding a home view, it has basically some prefix stuff.
It's even generated a Views directory with some sample pages.
And so your app.view out of the gate
is actually configured to already use.
You can see the router link here.
You can see the router view here.
So just know that what I did is to show you
how you might do that from scratch.
Most of the time, you're not going to be doing that.
It'll already be configured for you.
You're going to go in there and make some changes.
And so again, if you ever want a reference
on a clean way of how they did it,
you can always just scaffold the new project with it,
and you'll get everything you need.